[woman] Wait, you want me
to tell 'em what happened?
Well, two people got crabs,
and they were spreading.
We were all very hyper about it.
I have to go shower some people.
[chuckles] I'll see you later.
[man 1] I wanted to be part of the world,
but I didn't see anyone like me in it.
I hear about a summer camp
for the handicapped, run by hippies.
Somebody said you probably
will smoke dope with the counselors.
[chuckles] And I'm like, "Sign me up!"
Come to Camp Jened and find yourself.
There I was! I was at Woodstock.
[man 2] You wouldn't be picked
to be on the team back home.
But at Jened,
you had to go up to bat.
Even when we were that young,
we helped empower each other.
It was allowing us to recognize
that the status quo
is not what it needed to be.
[woman 2]
The world always wants us dead.
We live with that reality.
[man 1] At the time,
so many kids just like me
were being sent to institutions.
It was just a continual struggle.
Most disabled people, like myself,
are unable to use public transportation.
[man 1] We needed
a civil rights law of our own.
[reporter] A rehabilitation program
has been vetoed by the president
because it was cost prohibitive.
[woman 3] We decided we were
gonna have a demonstration.
[woman 4] You get the call to action.
"To the barricades!"
[reporter] A small army of the handicapped
have occupied this building
for the past 11 days.
[man 1] So many people from Camp Jened
found their way into the building.
[woman 2] The FBI cut off the phones.
The deaf people went,
"We know what to do."
That's how we communicated
to the people outside the building.
The Black Panther Party
would bring a hot meal.
We were like this.
[man over PA] We are the strongest
political force in this country.
We will no longer allow the government
to oppress disabled individuals.
And I would appreciate it if you would
stop shaking your head in agreement
when I don't think you understand
what we are talking about.
[man 1] What we saw at that camp
was that our lives could be better.
-[boy] Go!
-[man 3] Go!
[woman 5] If you don't demand
what you believe in for yourself,
you're not gonna get it.
♪ I sailed for pleasure ♪
Would you like to see the
handicapped people depicted as people?
Excuse me?